Register of the We Supported Our Men in Vietnam records
Hoover Institution Archives
We Supported Our Men in Vietnam records
1965-1995
1967-1968; 1987-1989
93057
Hoover Institution Archives
5 manuscript boxes, 10 oversize boxes, 7 motion picture film reels (15.1 linear feet)
Correspondence, clippings, scrapbooks, photographs, memorabilia, sound and video recordings, and motion picture film related to efforts in New York to mobilize popular support for American servicemen and prisoners of war in Vietnam both during and after the Vietnam War.
We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access. For access to other sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993 with an increment in 1995.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc. grew out of the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade, which was organized by New York fire chief Ray Gimmler in 1967. The parade was held on May 13, 1967 along 5th Avenue in New York City and included thousands of people in attendance. Gimmler was moved to organize the event after learning that demonstrators had burned the American flag during an anti-war demonstration in April of 1967. The goal of the parade was not only to counteract the growing anti-war movement of the time, but to show American servicemen in Vietnam that they had the support and backing of the American people.
Throughout the rest of the Vietnam War, the group was simply known as the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade Committee (sometimes also referred to as the Support Our Men in Vietnam Parade Committee). Gimmler continued to lead the group as director and chairman with John M. Connolly, Jr. and Frank J. D'Amico serving as co-directors. In addition to proving that the majority of Americans supported servicemen abroad, at this time the organization focused on many other issues related to the war, including the treatment of American prisoners of war (POWs) and soldiers who were missing in action (MIA). They established the Council for Civilized Treatment of POWs and became active members of other patriotic committees, such as the National Committee for Responsible Patriotism and the National Committee for the Protection of Patriotic Americans.
In 1973 the group helped organize another parade in New York City, the Home with Honor Parade. It was held on March 31, the day after the U.S. officially announced it would withdraw from Vietnam. Although smaller than the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade, the Home with Honor Parade also drew thousands of attendees. Participants marched from Times Square to Central Park behind approximately 1,000 servicemen who had recently returned home from the war.
In 1985 the organization officially changed its name to We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc. and shifted its focus to the creation and distribution of the documentary, At Home with Honor. It was composed of footage from different parades and events held for Vietnam servicemen, both during and after the war. For a full list of the events covered in the documentary, see note in the U-matic videocassettes section of the Audiovisual Material series.
During the organization's final years, the group distributed approximately 2,000 copies of At Home with Honor to American Legion posts, U.S. Veterans Affairs (VA) medical centers, and Air Force Reserve Officers’ Training Corps (ROTC) colleges. They also donated copies of the film to the National Archives and the Library of Congress and arranged for showings of the film at local community, veteran, and political organizations. On October 24, 1989, We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc. received a George Washington Honor Medal from the Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge for excellence in programs and activities for their work on At Home with Honor. The organization concluded its activities in 1995.
Scope and Content of Collection
The We Supported Our Men in Vietnam records contain correspondence, clippings, photographs, scrapbooks, memorabilia, motion picture film, and sound and video recordings that document the organization’s efforts to mobilize support for Americans who served in the Vietnam War. The materials in the collection span the active dates of the organization, from 1965 to 1995, with the majority of the materials being from the late 1960s and late 1980s.
Much of the material pertains to the Support Our Boys in Vietnam and Home with Honor parades, as well as the group’s documentary, At Home with Honor, created in 1985. In addition, the collection contains materials related to the Council for the Civilized Treatment of POWs Committee, a subdivision of the organization led by John M. Connolly, Jr., and other patriotic organizations that Chairman Ray Gimmler was active in.
The Correspondence series contains materials originally organized and housed in binders by the organization. It includes several letters of support and thanks from national and local New York government officials, members of the public, as well as servicemen and their families. It also contains letters to television studios, political figures, and various organizations arguing that the majority of Americans supported the troops during the Vietnam War, contrary to what was being depicted in the media. Press releases and clippings regarding the group’s activities and Vietnam veteran issues are intermixed throughout these files. More of this type of material, as well as photographs of events, can be found in scrapbooks in the Oversized Material series.
The Audiovisual Material series contains footage of the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade held in New York City on May 13, 1967, as well as recordings of Ray Gimmler’s radio and television appearances speaking on behalf of the organization. It also contains copies of the organization's documentary, At Home with Honor, which was sent to a number of military and veteran organizations along with a questionnaire about the film. Completed questionnaires can be found in the Projects and Events series.
Posters, signs, and buttons from the various events the group participated in can be found in the Memorabilia and Oversized Material series. This includes material used in the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade, a “Free the Pueblo” demonstration, and events regarding Vietnam POW/MIA issues.
Arrangement Statement
Within each series the materials were generally kept in the original arrangement and order of the creator. Original file names were also preserved and are denoted by quotation marks. It should also be noted that the organization often used the terms "boys" and "men" interchangeably in their name as well as in the title of their 1967 parade. For clarity, in this finding aid "boys" was used when referring to the 1967 parade and the organization prior to 1985 (i. e. Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade and Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade Committee), while "men" was used when referring to the organization after 1985 (i. e. We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc.).
Motion pictures.; Prisoners of war.; United States--Armed Forces.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Missing in action.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Prisoners and prisons, North Vietnamese.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Public opinion.
- Correspondence, 1967-1995 (Boxes 1-4)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains material originally housed in binders. It includes correspondence between the directors of We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc. and government officials, servicemen and their families, and members of the public with clippings, press releases, and other printed matter dispersed throughout. Much of the correspondence consists of letters of support regarding the We Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade and the documentary, At Home with Honor. Some of the correspondence also includes letters written by or for other patriotic organizations that the directors were involved with.
  Because the creator organized some of these files by subject and others by correspondent, it may be necessary to search several files that span the same date range when conducting research. Some correspondence also appears in the scrapbooks found in the Oversized Material series. File titles in quotations denote original file names used by the creator.
  - General, 1967-1995
    Contains material from unnamed files.
    - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1: 1-2)
    - 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1: 3-4)
    - 1990-1993 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - 1993-1995 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - "Letters,", 1967-1968
    - "Letters 1967-1968," (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - "Gove[r]nors and Dignitaries,", 1967 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - "NY State Officials and Legislature,", 1967 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - "City Officials,", 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - "Misc. and VIP Letters,", 1967 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      Includes correspondence with various political and community organizations.
    - "Military,", 1967 (Box-folder 2: 2-3)
  - "Letters from Organizations,", 1967-1968, undated (Box-folder 2: 4-6)
  - "Support Our [Boys] in Vietnam Parade,", 1967-1986
    Includes correspondence sent and received by members the group, then known as the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade Committee, and not necessarily about the parade itself.
    - "Best Letters from Servicemen in Vietnam War,", 1967 (Box-folder 2: 7)
      Includes letters from servicemen thanking Ray Gimmler for organizing the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade, some of which contain the writers' sentiments regarding how the anti- and pro-war movements in the United States are affecting them overseas.
    - "Misc. Letters,", 1967-1973 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
    - "Letters,", 1973-1986 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Letters and press, 1979-1989
    The term "corporation" in these files refers to We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc.
    - "Letters to Corporation,", 1988-1989 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - "Letters from Corporation,", 1988-1989 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - "Press Clips,", 1987-1989 (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - "[Pre-1989] Information,", 1979-1987 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - "At Home with Honor Documentary,", 1984-1993
    At Home with Honor was a documentary created by the organization in 1985 and distributed by them to various military, veterans, and political organizations. It contained footage of various events in the United States that were held in support of the servicemen in Vietnam. For a full description of footage contained in the film, see the Audiovisual Material series. The group also distributed a questionnaire to recipients of the film which can be found in the Projects and Events File series.
    - "Letters,", 1984-1986 (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
    - "Letters - Press,", 1990-1993 (Box-folder 4: 3-4)
    - Stock letters, 1990-1993
      - Air Force ROTC colleges, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 4: 5)
      - American Legion posts, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 6)
      - Follow-ups, 1990 (Box-folder 4: 7)
      - Veterans Affairs (VA) medical centers, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- Projects and Events File, 1967-1993 (Boxes 4-5)
  Comprised of photographs and documents relating to the planning and execution of the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade on May 13, 1967; the Home with Honor Parade on March 31, 1973; and the distribution of the At Home with Honor documentary. See also related scrapbooks in Oversized Material. Arranged chronologically.
  - Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade Committee file, 1967 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - "Home with Honor Parade and Photos, March 31, 1973," (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - "Home with Honor Documentary: ROTC, V.A. Hospitals, Veterans Questionnaire and Answers,", 1990-1993 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    Note
    For correspondence regarding the film, see the "At Home with Honor Documentary" file in the Correspondence series.
- Chairman's File, 1967-1990 (Box 5)
  Contains material related to the organization's funding, Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge award, and other material collected by We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc.'s chairman, Ray Gimmler.
  - Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge award, 1967, 1989
    - Nomination materials, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 3)
      Includes a "Prefacing Statement" which summarizes the group's goals and accomplishments to date.
    - October 24, 1989 awards ceremony (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Funding materials, 1989-1990, undated (Box-folder 5: 5)
    Includes contracts, proposals, questionnaires, and correspondence related to the organization's funding from New York State's Division of Veterans' Affairs.
  - Miscellany, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    Consists mainly of clippings and press releases related to We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc. and Ray Gimmler. Also includes typescripts of two speeches given by Ray Gimmler in 1989.
- Memorabilia, undated (Box 5)
  Contains stickers and pins with pro-American sentiments and messages regarding Vietnam War POWs, MIAs, and the "Free the Pueblo" incident.
  - Stickers, undated (Box-folder 5: 7)
    Contains 11 stickers and bumper stickers.
  - Pins, undated (Box-folder 5: 8)
    Contains 10 pins.
- Audiovisual Material, 1967-1989 (Boxes 14-15)
  Contains motion picture film as well as video and sound recordings of We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc. activities. Included are copies of the documentary At Home with Honor and recordings of Gimmler's various television and radio program appearances he made representing the organization. Material is arranged chronologically.
  - Moving images, 1967-1989
    - 16mm films, 1967-1971 (Film shelf)
      - Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade (3 hours), 1967 May 13
        Access
        Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 93057_f_0011997_r01.
        Footage of the parade held on May 13, 1967 on Fifth Avenue in New York City. Spans four reels.
      - Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade (30 minute version), 1967 May 13
      - Flag Day Ceremony, Yankee Stadium (7 minutes), 1967 June 14
        Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: 93057_f_0011995_r01.
      - Holland television documentary (34 minutes), 1971
        Documentary discussing the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade and related issues. Includes footage of the parade and of Police and Fire Appreciation Day held in Washington, D.C. on December 1, 1970.
    - U-matic video cassettes, 1985 (Box 14)
      - At Home with Honor, documentary (34 minute version), 1985
        Includes footage of the following events: Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade in New York City, May 13, 1967; Flag Day Ceremony at Yankee Stadium, June 14, 1967; Hard Hat Parade in New York City, May 20, 1970; Central Park flag raising ceremony, October 15, 1970; Home with Honor Parade in New York City, March 31, 1973; dedication of National Vietnam Memorial in Washington, D.C., 1984; dedication of New York City Vietnam Memorial, May 6, 1985; and Ticker Tape Parade in New York City, May 7, 1985.
      - At Home with Honor, documentary (29 minute version), 1985
    - VHS video cassettes, 1967-1989 (Box 15)
      - Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade on Fifth Ave in New York City (1 hour and 45 minutes), 1967 May 13
      - Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade on Fifth Ave in New York City (30 minute version), 1967 May 13
      - Flag Day Ceremony, Yankee Stadium (7 minutes), 1967
      - Holland television documentary (34 minutes), 1971
      - At Home with Honor, documentary (34 minute version), 1985
      - At Home with Honor, documentary (29 minute version), 1985
      - Recording of Ray Gimmler's television appearances (approximately 35 minutes), 1989 May
        Includes a May 28th appearance on the WWOR-TV, Channel 9 New Jersey television show "Point of View" and a May 29th appearance on Channel 12, Long Island Network News discussing Vietnam War parades.
  - Sound recordings, 1967-1989
    - Cassette tapes, 1970-1989 (Box 15)
      - David Suskind Show, WNEW-TV (2 hours), 1970 June 14
        Radio show discussing issues related to Support Our Boys in Vietnam. Spans two cassette tapes.
      - Barry Farber Show, WMCA Radio (2 hours), 1984
        Includes segements that aired on February 9 and March 3 of 1984 discussing issues related to Support Our Boys in Vietnam.
      - Joe Allen Show, WBAU Radio (1 hour), 1989 May 29
        Radio show discussing issues related to Support Our Boys in Vietnam and Home with Honor parades.
      - Ray Gimmler on Dialogue 101, WCBS Radio (30 minutes), 1989 October 15
    - Audio reels, 1967-1970 (Box 14)
      - Barry Farber Show, WOR Radio (3 hours), 1967 May 29
        Includes guests Ray Gimmler, Martin McNeely, Edward Patantonio, Charles Willis, Lewis Klein, and Leon Becker discussing the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade and veteran issues. Spans four reels.
      - Audio of Veterans Day memorial services at St. John's Park, Stanford, Connecticut (1 hour), 1967 November 11
        Includes recording of speech given by Ray Gimmler. Spans three reels.
      - Barry Farber Show, WOR Radio (3 hours), 1969 November 20
        Radio show discussing issues related to Support Our Boys in Vietnam. Spans eight reels.
      - Audio of Holland television documentary (30 minutes), 1970
        See video recording description of Holland documentary above.
- Oversized Material, 1965-1990 (Boxes 6-13)
  Comprised of We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc. event posters and scrapbooks documenting the organization's activities.
  - Posters, 1967-1985 (Box 13)
    Includes various posters from the Support Our Boys in Vietnam and Home with Honor parades, as well as other events the organization participated in.
  - Scrapbooks, 1965-1990
    The scrapbooks contain photographs, clippings, correspondence, and other printed matter documenting the organization's parades and other patriotic activities members participated in, especially related to the Vietnam War. Also included are material specific to Ray Gimmler's participation in other organizations, such as the American Legion. Scrapbooks have been unbound for preservation purposes.
    - "Support Our Boys in Vietnam,", 1965-1967 (Box 6)
      Includes material related to different demonstrations Ray Gimmler participated in with the East Rockaway American Legion in support of the troops in Vietnam.
    - Untitled, 1965-1984 (Box 7)
      Contains material related to the Support Our Boys in Vietnam Parade held on May 13, 1967, Vietnam veteran and POW issues, and the activities of group members, especially Ray Gimmler. Also includes several photographs of George Bush and meeting with the Council for the Civilized Treatment of P.O.W.s Committee at the United Nations on April 6, 1967.
    - "Support Our [Boys] in Viet Nam [sic] Parades,", 1967-1968 (Box 10)
    - "Free the Pueblo - 1968; Lights on for Decency - 1969,", 1968-1969 (Box 11)
    - "POW - MIA Issue - 1969-1983; Home with Honor Parade - 1973," (Box 12)
    - "POW - MIA Issue,", 1970-1972 (Box 6)
    - "POW - MIA Issue,", 1972-1975 (Box 8)
    - Untitled, 1983-1990 (Box 9)
      Contains primarily news clippings related to the return of Vietnam veterans to the United States. Also includes copies of correspondence relating to the At Home with Honor documentary and three photographs.